Guide to the Stuart Otto papers, 1918-1940.
Otto, Stuart papers, 1918-1940.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stuart Otto papers, 1918-1940.
2389
Stuart, Otto 1888-1962.
1.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, files, and typescript.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating mainly to Otto's contributions to the development of household refrigeration by gas. Included are records of the SORCO Manufacturing Company, Scranton, Pennsylvania, and its successor, the Gas Refrigeration Corporation, New York City. Also, Otto's correspondence concerning the refrigeration industry; files relating to patents on refrigeration machinery; and a typescript history of his involvement in the refrigeration business.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Businessman, inventor.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers relating mainly to Otto's contributions to the development of household refrigeration by gas. Included are records of the SORCO Manufacturing Company, Scranton, Pennsylvania, and its successor, the Gas Refrigeration Corporation, New York City. Also, Otto's correspondence concerning the refrigeration industry; files relating to patents on refrigeration machinery; and a typescript history of his involvement in the refrigeration business.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Otto, Stuart,1888-1962.; Gas Refrigeration Corporation (New York, N.Y.); Sorco Manufacturing Company (Scranton, Penn.)
Subjects:
Refrigeration and refrigerating machinery--Research.; Refrigeration industry--New York (N.Y.); Refrigeration industry--Pennsylvania--Scranton.; Inventors.
Form and Genre Terms:
Patents.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Patents of the Gas Refrigeration Company, 1923-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles, advertisements and catalogues re refrigerators, 1927-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photographs re refrigeration, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Financial records re Sorco Refrigerator Co., 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Orders to Crocker Chair Company, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto, 1933-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto with H. W. Tobey, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Gas Age-Record", 1925-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sectional Committee on safety Code for Mechanical Refrigeration, American Engineering Standards Committee, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and related documents re patents of the Gibson Electric Refrigerator Corporation, 1924-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto with representative of the Gibson Electric Refrigerator Co., 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto with officers of the National Refrigerator Co. largely re Refrigerator Safety Code, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Patent investigations of O'Neill and Bunn re Otto Refrigerator Apparatus including reply to Report by Dean, Fairbank, Obreight, and Hirsch and preliminary report by Ford, Bacon, and Davis, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence between Stuart Otto and Professor Ing R. Plank of the Kältetechnische Institute of Karlsruhe, 1926-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto with Sulzer Brothers of Switzerland re Refrigerator patents, 1926-1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence of Albert Otto and Sons with vatious individuals re room ventilation using the Temperain system of Korning and Co., 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence of Stuart Otto with United American Bosch Corp. re mfg. Of the Sorco Refrigerator, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Reports on the Sorco Refrigerator; Gas Refrigeration in general; and the Gas Refrigerator Co., 1922-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Testing records of Sorco Refirgerator, 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1927-1928 Sorco Refrigerator tests
  - 1934 Test of Smith, Sorco, Gibson at Bosch, Springfield
- Testing data including "Report of the Otto Mechanical Refrigerator" by Ford, Bacon, and Davis, Inc., engineers. Nov. 22, 1923, 1923, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence between Stuart Otto and Ford, Bacon and Davis, Engineers, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Advertising records, including agreement for underwriting co., stock certificate for shares in Gas Refrigeration Company, and 1933 report to stockholders in the Gas Refrigeration Co., 1924, 1927, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Construction instructions for Gas Operated Refrigerator, No Date (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous correspondence re the Sorco Refrigerator and patents on "iceless refrigerators", 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Manufacturing and service records, Sorco Co., 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- References, articles, pamphlets, books, clippings and offprints re refrigerators and Refrigerators, c. 1924-1936 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Misc. small blueprints, charts, drawings, and lists of such items, 1927, 1933, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Confidential description of Stuart Otto Automatic Iceless Refrigerator, 1923, and specifications and description of Sorco refrigerator, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Patent information re the Sorco Refrigerator and related inventions (I), 1922-1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Patent information re the Sorco Refrigerator and related inventions (I), 1918-1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles and brochures re the Sorco Refrigerator and related inventions, 1923-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ortto Mechanical Refrigerator, estimated production costs and cash statements, 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Refrigerator drawings, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Complete set of drawings "E series", 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Robers Bosch AG, 1929, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous drawings and blueprints Sorco Refrigerator, 1923-1934 (Box 3, Folder 3-Feb)
- Financial records and printing material, 1925-1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)